(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-09T03:03:11.762839",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
裏路地の真ん中で
In the middle of a back alley,
慣れない景色と好かない匂いに
surrounded by unfamiliar scenery and a scent I don't like,
私は覆われて
I am completely covered...
染まっていくんでしょう
...and will probably be dyed in them, right?
私は怖がりで
Because I'm a coward,
知らないことには手をつけず
I won't touch things I don't know.
誰かがやって来て
Waiting for someone else to come along...
毒味をするまで待っていた
...and test the poison first.
することは単純で
My routine is simple:
マニュアル通りの生活を
living life straight from a manual,
来る日も淡々と過ごしていた
spending day after day indifferently.
そういやさ そういやさ
Come to think of it, come to think of it,
昨日の私もこうだった
yesterday I was just like this too.
そういやさ そういやさ
Come to think of it, come to think of it...
弱い音を吐いてる
Spitting out weaknesses,
薄っぺらい人間です
I am such a shallow human being.
一歩前に出るのはやめときます
I'll pass on taking a step forward,
絡まれたくはないからさ
because I don't want to get involved with anyone.
描いた理想像に
Since the ideal image I drew
現実味がないから
lacks any sense of reality,
近づけないよう生きておきます
I'll live to keep my distance from it.
明日も同じよう過ごしておきます
And I'll spend tomorrow the same way too.
路地裏の真ん中で
In the middle of the back alley,
いつもの夕日を薄目で眺めて
staring at the usual sunset with squinted eyes,
胸の内で呟いた
I muttered in my heart,
いつまで続くだろう
"How long will this go on?"
そういやさ そういやさ
Come to think of it, come to think of it,
昨日も夕飯これだった
yesterday's dinner was this too.
そういやさ そういやさ
Come to think of it, come to think of it...
臆病でキリが悪い
With endless cowardice,
意気地無し人間です
I am a spineless human being.
一歩後ろに下がって逃げておきます
I'll take a step back and run away,
目立ちたくなんかないからさ
because I don't want to stand out at all.
描いた理想像に
Since the ideal image I drew
現実味がないから
lacks any sense of reality,
近づけないよう生きておきます
I'll live to keep my distance from it.
明日も同じよう過ごしておきます
And I'll spend tomorrow the same way too.
弱い音を吐いてる
Spitting out weaknesses,
薄っぺらい人間です
I am such a shallow human being.
一歩前に出るのはやめときます//I'll pass on taking a step forward,
I'll pass on taking a step forward,
絡まれたくはないからさ
because I don't want to get involved with anyone.
ため息ばっかでさ
Doing nothing but sighing,
吸う息足りないの
I don't even have enough breath to inhale.
きっとそう上手くはいかないけどさ
Things surely won't go that well, but...
試しにちょっと生きてみよう
...let's try to live just a little bit anyway.
鉄の弾が正義の証明
An iron bullet is proof of justice.
貫けば 英雄に近づいた
If it pierces through, you're closer to a hero.
その目を閉じて
Close your eyes...
同じ形同じ体温の悪魔
A devil with the same shape and temperature.
僕はダメであいつはいいの？
Am I no good, but they are fine?
そこに壁があっただけなのに
Even though there was just a wall there.
生まれてしまった 運命嘆くな
Don't lament the fate of being born,
僕らはみんな 自由なんだから
because we are all free.
鳥のように 羽があれば
If we had wings like birds,
どこへだって行けるけど
we could go anywhere,
帰る場所が なければ
but if we have no place to go back to,
きっとどこへも行けない
we surely cannot go anywhere.
ただただ生きるのは嫌だ
I just don't want to live in vain.
世界は残酷だ
The world is cruel,
それでも君を愛すよ
but I still love you.
なにを犠牲にしても
No matter what I sacrifice,
それでも君を守るよ
I will still protect you.
間違いだとしても 疑ったりしない
Even if it's wrong, I won't doubt you.
正しさとは 自分のこと 強く信じることだ
Righteousness is believing in yourself strongly.
鉄の雨が 降り散る情景 テレビの中 映画に見えたんだ
The rain of steel falling looked like a movie on TV.
戦争なんて 愚かな凶暴 関係ない 知らない国の話
War is just foolish violence, an irrelevant story of a foreign country.
それならなんで あいつ憎んで 黒い気持ち 隠しきれない理由
If so, why do I hate them? The reason for my dark feelings I can't hide,
説明だって できやしないんだ
I can't even explain it.
僕らはなんて 矛盾ばっかなんだ
We are nothing but contradictions.
この言葉も 訳されれば 本当の意味は伝わらない
Even these words, if translated, won't convey their true meaning.
信じるのは その目を開いて 触れた世界だけ
All I believe is the world I touched with my eyes wide open.
ただただ生きるのは嫌だ
I just don't want to live in vain.
世界は残酷だ
The world is cruel,
それでも君を愛すよ
but I still love you.
なにを犠牲にしても
No matter what I sacrifice,
それでも君を守るよ
I will still protect you.
選んだ人の影 捨てたものの屍
The shadow of the chosen, the corpses of the discarded.
気づいたんだ 自分の中 育つのは悪魔の子
I realized that what grows inside me is a child of the devil.
正義の裏 犠牲の中 心には悪魔の子
Behind justice, amidst sacrifice, in my heart is a child of the devil.
そっと振り返った軌跡 どうしたって光って
Looking back softly at our path, it shines no matter what.
ありふれた君が いつだってスーパーヒーロー
Ordinary you are always my superhero.
いつもポンコツだった私 飛べなくて未完成
I was always useless, unable to fly and incomplete.
アヒルの子はアヒルのままかもね、なんてさ
"Maybe the ugly duckling will stay a duckling," I said.
らしさ、なんてほっといて 君となんかちょっと似ていて
Never mind being "true to oneself," we are somewhat alike.
デコボコだからジャストに噛み合うパズルピース
Since we're uneven, we fit perfectly like puzzle pieces.
繋げたい 繋げたい 届かない言葉も
I want to connect, I want to connect, even the words that won't reach.
いつかは誰かの何かに成りたいから
Because someday I want to become something to someone.
crazy no lazy 夢の中 夢を見せて
Crazy, no lazy, show me a dream within a dream.
always going
何千回 何万回 膝をついても
No matter how many thousands or tens of thousands of times my knees give out,
最大級 i love you で立ち上がれるから
I can stand back up with the greatest "I love you".
とびきりオーバーな ty
An extraordinarily huge thank you.
消えそうなハッピーも勇気も
Even the happiness and courage that seem to fade away,
振り絞っちゃって
Squeezing it all out...
大失敗も後悔さえ愛せるなら
If I can love even great failures and regrets,
背中には 君という羽
Then on my back are wings called "you."
チックタック追い越して
Overtaking the tick-tock,
いつもと変わらない日常？そうか
Is this just the usual everyday life?
隣で走る君と Release, Release
Running alongside you, release, release,
響き渡る
Resound,
No fiction
君の色が 私を塗り替えて
Your color repaints me,
壊れかけの音で響くから
As it resonates with a half-broken sound.
お伽話の 続きをまだ描きたいんだよ
I still want to draw the sequel to the fairy tale.
palette palette 連れて行くよ
Palette, palette, I'll take you with me.
きっと何千回何万回
Surely thousands, tens of thousands of times,
Always going
何千回何万回 迷い込んでも
Even if I get lost thousands, tens of thousands of times,
最大級 I love you な君がいるから
Because there's you, whom I love to the maximum degree,
更新中 Special な Thank you
Updating a special thank you.
そう、誰だって
Yes, anyone
ラッキーも運命も手繰り寄せて
Can pull in luck and destiny,
もうバイバイも涙も忘れないよ
So I won't forget goodbyes or tears anymore.
飛べなかった私の
On the back of my once-flightless self,
この背中には
On this back of mine,
君という羽
Are wings called "you."
描いた未来の景色がここにある
The scene of the future we drew is right here.
弱さも抱きしめていくから
Since I'll embrace even my weaknesses,
広げた翼が輝いていく
The spread-out wings will keep shining.
旅立とう 私と
Let's embark on a journey, with me.
等身大の私を写していたい、ただ
I want to reflect my true, authentic self, simply.
望む瞬間 衝動になってんだ
The moment I desire, it becomes an impulse.
くだらないとか 曇りきっていく目をして
With eyes clouding over and calling things pointless,
可能性だって夢を見てみたいのに
Even though I want to dream of possibilities.
ずっと分かっていたんだけど
I've always known, but...
言葉は浮ついている 対象に
My words are floating aimlessly towards the target.
大袈裟だって思っているんでしょ
You think it's exaggerated, don't you?
ずっと黙っていたんだけど
I've always stayed silent, but...
心ってやっぱり正直だ
My heart is honest after all.
打ち込まれた色を感じたい気がしている
I feel like I want to experience the infused colors.
ここだよ 響かせて
I'm here, let it resonate.
焦がしたこの場所で
In this place I yearned for,
解けないでいてよ
Please don't fade away.
明かりになっていく
It is turning into a light.
何度も失われた 取り返した意志の強さに
By the strength of my will, repeatedly lost and reclaimed,
誓った
I swore to it.
失敗 後悔はないって 溜息の音を消している
Drowning out the sound of sighs, saying there is no failure or regret,
現状に不安はない 飲み込んだ気取っていたんだ
I swallowed my lack of anxiety about the current state, pretending.
忘れないように
So that I won't forget,
金輪際 もう汚されないように
Never again, so that it won't be tainted.
もっと笑っていたいんだもの
Because I want to laugh more,
大人になっていく代償に
As the price of growing up.
あなただってきっと思っているんでしょ
Surely you, too, must be thinking that.
ちゃんと分かっていたんだけど
I understood it perfectly, but...
心ってやっぱり正直だ
My heart is honest after all.
薄れなくなった痛みを 感じたい気がしている
I feel like I want to experience the pain that won't fade.
閉ざされたこの場所で
In this closed place,
咲かせたってほら
Look, even if I make it bloom,
解けないでいてよ
Please don't fade away.
拒まない明日を待っている
I am waiting for a tomorrow that won't reject me,
何度も
Countless times,
奪われた
It was stolen.
取り戻した日々の傷跡に 誓った
I swore on the scars of the days I reclaimed.
心よ響かせて
Let my heart resonate!
心を響かせて
Let my heart resonate,
ずっと
forever.
ここだよ 響かせて 掲げたこの腕で Never mind でしょう
I'm right here! Let it resonate! With this raised arm, it's "never mind," right?
右左だって 自由になっていく 何度も
Even left and right become free, over and over again!
見失い、取り戻した日々の傷跡に 誓った
I swore on the scars of the days I lost and reclaimed.
はい！
Yes! Phew...
皆さん！
Everyone!
というわけで、本日は常闇トワ生誕祭2025にお越しくださりありがとうございます！
And so, thank you so much for coming to Towa Tokoyami Birthday Festival 2025 today!
こんやっぴー！ホロライブ4期生の常闇トワです！
Konyappi! I'm Towa Tokoyami from Hololive 4th Gen!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はぁ、ちょっと水飲んでもいいですか？
Phew, is it okay if I drink some water?
水もらっていいですか、すみません。
Can I get some water, please? Sorry.
ちょっとあのすみませんね、あ、水…
Wait, sorry, ah, water...
あ、そっか、どこに行ってもカメラがね、映るのよね。
Ah, right, the camera captures me wherever I go, doesn't it?
はぁ、水おいしい。
Ah, water is delicious.
ということでね、皆さん！今日はライブにお越しいただきありがとうございます！
So, everyone! Thank you so much for coming to the live show today!
3Dライブをやらせていただいております。ということでね、
I'm holding a 3D live concert. And with that said...
えー、早速なんですけれども、
well, without further ado,
ありがとう！みんなおめでとう、ありがとう！
Thank you! Congrats everyone, thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
見えてますよ。
I can see you!
はい、早速なんですけれどもね、
Yes, so without further ado,
今回の配信のハッシュタグはこちら！
here is the hashtag for today's stream!
ハッシュタグ常闇トワ生誕祭2025ということでね、
It's #常闇トワ生誕祭2025!
こちらね、Xでたくさんポストしていただければなと思います。
I hope you can post a lot on X with this.
えー、スクリーンショットとかね、感想もいっぱいいただけたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you share screenshots and your thoughts, too.
えーっと、スクショはね、もしかしてね、
And regarding the screenshots, if...
えー、素敵なのがあったらちょっと、パク、パクるというか、
if there are some nice ones, I might... steal them? Or rather,
あの、拝借というか、何というか、何て言うんですかね？
borrow them, or how should I put it?
はい、あの、あの、勝手に「これ使っちゃおう！」みたいな感じで使って、
Yeah, I might casually go "I'll use this!" and post it
あの、これ終わった後にポストするかもしれないんですけども、
after the stream is over.
そのために撮っておいてくれたらな、みたいな、手伝ってくれたらなと思います。よろしくお願いいたします。
So I'd appreciate it if you could take some for that purpose to help me. Thank you!
フレームワークの共有ね！言いかね、
Sharing the framework! A nice way to put it,
フレームワークの共有だね。
it's sharing the framework.
はい。えー、そしてね、本日はライブだけじゃなくて、
Yes. And today, not only the live performance,
色んなね、発表も、えー、したいと思いますので、
but we also have various announcements to make,
えー、最後まで見ていてくれれば嬉しいです、はい。
so I'd be happy if you stay with us until the end!
えー、ここまなんですけれども、
So up to this point,
えー、1曲目にね、和ぬかさんの楽曲の『ヨワネハキ』
for the first song, I sang Wanuka-san's "Yowanehaki."
2曲目に、樋口アイさんの『悪魔の子』
For the second, Higuchi Ai-san's "Akuma no Ko."
そしてトワのオリジナル曲の『S.T.Y.』と『Present Day』を歌わせていただきました。
And then I sang Towa's original songs "S.T.Y." and "Present Day."
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
今日のね、配信のオープニングは『Present Day』のインストを使ってます。
Today's opening for the stream used the instrumental of "Present Day."
テンション上がるよね！
It pumps you up, doesn't it?
はい、この曲かっこいい、かっこいいけど入りが難しいんで、
Yes, this song is so cool. It's cool, but the entry is hard,
いっつも、あの皆さんに聞こえないとこでクリックをつけてもらってます。
so I always have them play a click track where you guys can't hear it.
ふふふ、恥ずかしいんですけども、すごい難しいから、はい。
Hehe, it's a bit embarrassing, but it's really hard, yes.
そしてね、今日はね、ちょっとモリモリに、
And today, there's a lot of information,
情報がモリモリなんだけど、歌もね、皆さんに、お届けしたいと思いますので、
a ton of it, but I also want to deliver songs to you,
一回ここでちょっと落ち着いて、次の曲にね、いきたいと思います。
so let me calm down a bit here and move on to the next song.
いっぱいね、発表が、したいと思いますので、
Since I want to make a lot of announcements,
あの、本当に、待っててください。はい。
please stay tuned. Yes.
ということで次の曲、オリジナル楽曲続きになります。
So for the next song, it's another original song.
えー、聞いてください。My Abyss。
Please listen to: My Abyss.
堕 堕 堕 沈んでいく dirty value
Down, down, down... sinking, dirty value
怒 怒 怒 忘れて交じり合う who am i ?
Rage, rage, rage... forgetting and blending, who am I?
目 目 目 這い寄る この 気持ち は もう
Eyes, eyes, eyes... creeping in, this feeling is already...
溶け て 消え ていく
melting away and disappearing.
絡まった 導火線 には 火花 近づけ play on
Bring the spark close to the tangled fuse, play on!
朽ちてった
Decaying...
倫理観には
To ethical standards...
近づけて
bring it closer.
あなたはどうしたい？ I wanna feel you closer
What do you want to do? I wanna feel you closer
I wanna be your master
悔い溶け合うまで踊りましょう
Let's dance until our regrets melt together.
目が合うのは誰
Whose eyes am I meeting?
深い闇へ堕ちていく
Falling into the deep darkness.
手を伸ばせ あなたまで届きますように
Stretch out your hand, I hope it reaches you.
Climb high
光射す先まで あなたの手を
To where the light shines, your hand...
取れますように
I hope I can take it.
I will
光射す先には
Where the light shines,
どこまでも広がる deep abyss
the deep abyss spreads endlessly.
彷徨っていた in the dark room
I was wandering in the dark room,
それでも欲しいんだ moon
but I still want the moon.
もう止まらない greed & freedom
Unstoppable greed & freedom,
全部手に入れよう everywhere
let's get it all, everywhere.
Hey, this is underground 悪っぽい奴が勝ちのよう
Hey, this is underground, it seems the wicked win.
我慢しなくてもいいんじゃない？ もう こっちにおいで
Don't you think you don't have to hold back? Come over here already.
惹き寄せて 目にキスを
Draw closer, a kiss on the eyes.
手に取ったら make you evil
If you take it, it will make you evil.
火照った肌に触れた 近づけて
Touched the hot skin, bringing it closer.
あなたはどうしたい？ I wanna be your master
What do you want to do? I wanna be your master.
悔いすべて忘れて welcome to my paradise
Forget all regrets, welcome to my paradise.
ダダダ沈んでいく dirty value
Sinking down, down, down... dirty value.
トトト忘れて 混ざり合う fever night
Forget, get, get, blending on this fever night.
メメメ這い寄る この気持ちはもう
Creeping, creeping, creeping, this feeling is already...
Loop, loop 絡まった独占欲
Loop, loop, this tangled monopolistic desire.
今、近づけば くっついて
Now, if you get closer, we'll stick together.
倫理観には近づけて
Bring it closer to ethical standards.
あなたはどうしたい？ I wanna be your slave
What do you want to do? I wanna be your slave.
悔い溶け合うまで踊りましょう
Let's dance until our regrets melt together.
目が合うのは誰
Whose eyes am I meeting?
深い闇へ堕ちていく
Falling into the deep darkness.
駆け出せ この闇から逃げ出せるように Climb high
Run out, so we can escape from this darkness. Climb high.
光射す先まで あなたの手を掴めたら I will
To where the light shines, if only I could grab your hand. I will.
光射す先には
Where the light shines,
どこまでも広がる
it spreads endlessly,
どこまでも深く
deeply, endlessly,
どこまでも続いている deep abyss
endlessly continuing, the deep abyss.
堕ちていく
Falling down...
昔々悪魔の娘が顔のない国作ったとさ
Once upon a time, a devil's daughter created a faceless land.
やがて多くの人々が集い賑わった
Soon, many people gathered and it bustled with life.
娘はいたく喜び迎え入れたが
The daughter joyfully welcomed them, but...
顔のない人々は自ら神を名乗り始めた
the faceless people began to call themselves gods.
Oh... Talk to, talk to, devil, talk to, talk...
顔のない神様の言う通り
Just as the faceless gods say,
供物は甘いほど イイこどもたちの邪教
the sweeter the offering, the better for their heretical cult.
あれが欲しい これが欲しい 暴れては駄々こねる
“I want that, I want this,” throwing tantrums.
バズビバザヴ そろそろわからせてこ
Buzvibhavazav, it's about time we teach them a lesson.
瞬く間に あっちゅうまに 悪魔に
In the blink of an eye, into devils,
見る見る 悪魔に
right before your eyes, into devils.
瞬く間に あっちゅうまに 悪魔に
In the blink of an eye, into devils,
あくまで 悪魔に
to the very end, devils.
さあ 列成せ 平伏せ
Now, line up and prostrate yourselves,
奇跡ご覧あれ バズビバザヴ バズビバザヴ
behold the miracle, Buzvibhavazav! Buzvibhavazav!
Order!
滑稽ね 眩々するほど イラつくわ
How ridiculous, it's dizzyingly annoying.
なにこれ？ 邪魔だから踏んづけちゃお
What is this? You're in the way, so I'll stomp on you.
“魔心”を歌い踊る よたりよたり
Singing and dancing to the “devilish heart,” tottering along.
えー ヤバくない？ マズくない？
Whoa, isn't this bad? Isn't this risky?
声合わせ唱えましょう
Let's raise our voices and chant,
バズビバザヴ！
Buzvibhavazav!
聖母降臨 ダンスタイム
The descent of the Holy Mother, dance time.
深く ファナティック
Deep and fanatic
浸す ロマンティック
Immersive and romantic
「べきだ」とかの ノーサンキューです
Saying "it should be" is a "no thank you"
個人的な感想とか
Whether it's your personal impressions
あの先の妄想とか
Or wild delusions about the future...
は？ マジ終わってるんですけど
Huh? That's seriously messed up.
Listen up!
ちょっと attention!
Pay attention for a moment!
瞬く間に あっちゅう間に 悪魔に
In the blink of an eye, in a flash, turning into a devil
見る見る悪魔に
Right before your eyes, turning into a devil
瞬く間に あっちゅう間に 悪魔に
In the blink of an eye, in a flash, turning into a devil
あくまで悪魔に
To the absolute end, turning into a devil
Guilty
Duty
Stupid
Majesty
バズビ
Buzzvi
Order
反吐が出ちゃうぐるぐるするほど愛しいわ
It's so lovely that it makes me feel dizzy and nauseous
ブランニュー 邪教なら
If it's a brand new heresy,
ここが聖地
This is the holy ground.
崇めて
Worship me,
私に集え集え
Gather around me, gather around
合図は 666
The signal is 666
赦しを お慈悲を って 鳴いていいんじゃない？
Why not beg for "forgiveness" and "mercy"?
昔 悪魔の娘が 顔のない国 作ったとさ
Once upon a time, a devil's daughter created a faceless nation
やがて 多くのヒトビトが 集い賑わった
Eventually, many people gathered and it bustled with life
魔心を 歌い踊る
Singing and dancing to the devil's heart
よたりよたり
Reeling and swaying
これってヤバくない？ コワくない？
Isn't this crazy? Isn't it scary?
声合わせ唱えましょう
Let's raise our voices and chant together
バズビバザヴ！
Buzz Viva Zav!
響かす song
Make the song resound!
Talk talk
さぁ降臨だ、ダンスタイム
Now, descend, it's dance time!
心の奥で、残響がする。
An echo resonates deep within my heart.
それは、
Is it...
過去を超えるための進化か。
...evolution to overcome the past?
魂の奥底へ潜る深化か。
...deepening, plunging to the depths of the soul?
己の存在を証明する真価か。
...or the true value that proves my existence?
揺らぎ、信じ、見つけ出した心の芯。
Wavering, believing, and finding the core of my heart.
常闇を裂き、偽りのノイズを消し去って、
Tearing through eternal darkness, erasing the false noise,
いま、真実の歌声を
...now, I will make my true singing voice...
2ndアルバム発売決定
[Title: 2nd Album Release Decided]
SHIN (Tokoyami Towa 2nd Album "SHIN")
参加アーティスト
[Title: Participating Artists]
響き渡る、始まりの『SHIN』
Resounding, the beginning of 'SHIN'
はい！
Yes!
ということで、みなさん！
And with that, everyone!
常闇トワの、セカンドアルバム！
Tokoyami Towa's second album...
「SHIN」の、発表が…発表じゃないわ！発売が決定しました！
..."SHIN", has been announ—no, not announced! The release has been decided!
はい！ありがとうございます！
Yes! Thank you so much!
お待たせしました！
Sorry to keep you waiting!
はい、今回のジャケットイラストは、花邑まいさんに描き下ろしていただきました！
Yes, this album's jacket illustration was newly drawn by Mai Hanamura-san!
めっちゃかっこいいでしょう、これ！
Isn't this super cool?!
鎖引きちぎってね！よいしょ！って感じで。ね、話そう！
Tearing the chains apart, like "Heave-ho!". Let's talk about it!
はい！そしてね、10月8日、トワの日ですね！これちょっと設定させていただきました！
Yes! And on October 8th—which is "Towa Day"! I set it for this day!
10月8日から今回も、ファーストに続き、全国流通での発売となっております！
Starting October 8th, just like the first one, it will be released nationwide!
はい、ありがとうございます！
Yes, thank you so much!
豪華作家陣の皆様に書き下ろしていただいた新曲がたくさん収録されております！
It includes many new songs written by an amazing lineup of creators!
ジャケットいいでしょう？
The jacket looks great, right?
もう、もっと言って！ものすごい素敵なジャケット書いてくれました。本当に嬉しいです。
Please, say more! They drew such a wonderful jacket. I'm so happy.
そしてね、セカンドアルバムなんですけれども、完全生産限定盤と通常盤の2種類をご用意しております。
And, about this second album, we have two editions: the Limited Complete Edition and the Standard Edition.
まず、完全生産限定盤はこちら！
First, here is the Limited Complete Edition!
じゃーん！あ、こっちだった！
Ta-da! Ah, it was on this side!
外箱がね、超豪華スリーブボックスになっております！
The outer box is a super luxurious sleeve box!
はい。はいだって、はい。彼方書いて、はい。
Yes. "Yes" indeed, yes. Kanata wrote "yes."
そして中身はこちら！
And here are the contents!
アクリルブロックキーホルダーや、アナザージャケットカード、サイン入りオリジナルグッズなどが当たる、抽選応募券！
An acrylic block keychain, an alternative jacket card, and a lottery application ticket to win signed original merchandise!
6種類のMVカットステッカーセット！
A set of MV cut stickers featuring 6 designs!
あとはですね、hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PRカードの常闇トワなどなど、豪華特典がたくさん入っております！
And also, a Tokoyami Towa promo card from the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME, and many other deluxe bonuses!
ボックスなんですけれどもね、通常のCDよりもちょっと一回り二回りぐらい大きい、あの、本当に限定盤の、その、飾る用というか、そういう感じの、プレミアム感がついた...
Speaking of the box, it's about one or two sizes larger than a regular CD box. It's truly a limited edition designed for display, giving it a premium feel...
ような、えー、ボックスの、えー、限定盤となっております。
...making it a box, limited-edition package.
はい！そしてね、アナザージャケットカードには、ランダムでトワのね、直筆サインが入っております！
Yes! And a handwritten signature by Towa is randomly included in the Another Jacket Card!
はい！えー、そしてね、プレゼントキャンペーン商品のラインナップはこちらです！
Yes! And here is the lineup for the giveaway campaign!
ポン！
Ta-da!
はい！このね、キービジュアル…キービジュアルって言うの？これ違うか。えー、ライブのジャケ写、ジャケ写？ジャケ写か。
Yes! These use the key visual... Or is it key visual? Maybe not. Ah, the album cover, cover? Yeah, the cover art.
ジャケット写真を使った、Tシャツとか、ポスターとか、缶バッジがね、
T-shirts, posters, and button badges featuring the cover art...
えー、できてます！カッコいいでしょう？
...have been made! Cool, isn't it?
はい！
Yes!
カッコいいの欲しいよね。トワも、トワも欲しい、ごめんけど。
You want these cool items, right? Towa wants them too, honestly.
だからトワが、じゃあ1枚取るから、2名様と、9名様と…
So Towa will take one, meaning there are only 2 spots, 9 spots left...
嘘です、嘘嘘！皆さん、皆さんのためにちゃんとありますから！はい！
Just kidding, just kidding! They are all for you guys! Yes!
そしてね、続いて通常盤はこちらです！
Next, here is the regular edition!
はい！顔のね、ちょっとアップがポーンって入ったような、
Yes! This one features a close-up of my face, boom!
カッコいい、もう、目、もう釘付けでしょう、トワの顔に。はい。
So cool, your eyes will be glued to Towa's face! Yes.
えー、こちらのね、えー、デザインとなっておりまして。通常盤には、スマホサイズのジャケットイラストステッカーが入っております。
That's the design. The regular edition includes a smartphone-sized cover art sticker.
こちらのね、カッコいいジャケ写の、えー、ステッカー、
This cool cover art sticker...
スマホに貼ったり、PCに貼ったり、
...can be stuck on your phone, PC,
えー、何ですか、えー、レバレスとかに貼ったりとかね、アケコンに貼ったりとかしてもらえると嬉しいですと。はい！
leverless controller, arcade stick, or wherever you like! Yes!
そしてね、えー、こちら！今回のアルバムに楽曲を書き下ろしてくださった作家陣の皆様はこちらです！
And next! Here are the creators who wrote songs for this album!
ボーン！実あね、えー、さっき、えー、和ぬかさんの「ヨワネハキ」だとか、えー、ヒグチアイさんの「悪魔の子」だとか歌ってるけど、なんと！
Boom! Actually, I sang Wanuka-san's "Yowanehaki" and Higuchi Ai-san's "Akuma no Ko" earlier, and guess what!
書いてくれているんですよ。書き下ろしてもらいました！
They both wrote songs for me! They wrote new songs for this album!
実は伏線だったっていうね。
That was actually foreshadowing.
はい、ちょっとそういう感じで、ちょっと組ませていただきました。イェーイ！
Yes, I set up the setlist like that. Yay!
はい、そうなんですよ。
Yes, that's right.
あとね、まあ色々、まあ、見てびっくりすることもあると思うんですけども。
Also, I'm sure there are other things that will surprise you.
あ、この前の「My Abyss」が収録されてたりとか、「バズビバザブ」があったりとかしておりますと。
Like including the recent "My Abyss," or having "Bazubibazabu" on it.
はい、どの楽曲もすごい素敵に仕上がりなんでね、楽しみにしていてもらえればと思います。
Yes, every track turned out amazing, so please look forward to it.
はい！そして、各店舗別の特典はこちら！ボーン！
Yes! And here are the store-specific bonuses! Boom!
もういろんな種類がいっぱいあるからね、
There are so many different kinds!
もうどの特典も欲しくなると思うんですけども、全部買ってもよし、選んで買ってもよしということで、
I'm sure you'll want all of them, but you can buy them all or choose your favorites!
ひとつひとつ紹介したいところ、これを全部紹介すると多分5年くらい経つんでね、自分で見てくださいと。
I'd love to introduce them one by one, but that would probably take five years, so please check them yourself.
完全生産限定盤も通常盤も、絶対に手に入れてくださいと。
Make sure to get both the limited edition and the regular edition!
そして、こちらはね、本日21時から発売開始なんですが、ががが、ホロライブ公式ECでは、なんとこの配信中、
And sales start tonight at 9:00 PM, but... on the official hololive shop, during this stream...
えーっと、
Um...
え、なんですが、ががが、なんとホロライブ公式ECでは（編集点）、えー、この配信中に、
But, during this stream, on the official hololive shop (edit point!)...
CDが買えるようになるかも？何か出てきてポチって押せたりする、かかかかかも。ということで楽しみに待っててください。
...you might be able to buy the CD! Maybe something will pop up so you can click to buy it. So please look forward to it!
はい。
Yes.
このあとですね、そして、えー、次の曲はなんとこのあとからね、このあと、えー、セカンドアルバムから1曲、新曲を披露します。
And after this, for the next song, I will perform a new track from the second album!
えー、なるせさん、えー、GTAとかでね、お世話になっているなるせ兄貴、お兄ちゃんね、
nqrse-san, my nqrse-aniki—big brother—who took care of me in GTA and such,
書き下ろしていただきました、「chewy chewy」という楽曲になります。
...wrote this song for me. It's called "chewy chewy."
はい、この新曲「chewy chewy」はですね、この配信のあとに、MVが8時50分からプレミア公開、えー、24時に先行リリース予定です。
Yes, the music video for this new song "chewy chewy" will premiere at 8:50 PM after this stream, and the digital pre-release is at midnight!
やっぱね、なるせさんと言ったらね、ラップじゃないですか。
After all, when you think of nqrse-san, you think of rap, right?
で、この曲にラップがあるのかどうなのかっていうのは、まあ、このあと歌いますから、楽しみにしていてほしいです。
As for whether this song has rap or not... well, I'm singing it next, so please look forward to finding out!
このMVに関してはですね、普段ちょっとやったことない動きをね、あの、ディレクターさんに「こう動いてほしい」とか「ああ動いてほしい」とか言われながら試行錯誤して頑張ってやったんで、
For the music video, I tried hard to make some moves I don't normally do, trial and error style, while the director instructed me how to move.
ちょっと違和感もあるかもしれないけど、頑張ったトワがね、見れるMVになって…あ、スタイリッシュな感じのね、MVに仕上がりました。
It might feel a bit unusual, but you'll see a hard-working Towa, and the MV turned out very stylish.
なので、えー、このあとのプレミア公開は楽しみに待っていてくれればなと思います。
So please look forward to the premiere later!
そしてね、このあと、えー、なるせさんが書き下ろしてくださった「chewy chewy」を歌いたいと思いますので、
And now, I'd like to perform "chewy chewy," written by nqrse-san.
ぜひ、えー、ちょっと待って、ここで落ち着かないとね。ぜひ、えー、聴いていただければと思います。では、「chewy chewy」。
Please, ah... wait, I need to calm down here. Please listen. Now, "chewy chewy."
シュガー＆ココアのボーイ
Sugar and cocoa boy,
キレモノのボーイ
a sharp-witted boy.
耳隠しのコーストコースト飛ばすトワ
Hiding my ears, flying coast to coast, this is Towa.
Colorにならう　高ぶる性にならう
Flowing with the colors, following my passionate nature.
針落とす　同時に問いと散らす Let's go!
Drop the needle, dispersing questions and intents simultaneously. Let's go!
待つ賛美と自由で縛ってく
Binding them with the praise and freedom that await.
のが上手だなんて
...at making excuses.
苦労苦労 回避お上手だって
And you're so good at avoiding trouble.
でも No Pain, No Gain
But no pain, no gain.
どのハートも時計仕掛け
Every heart is like clockwork.
任されたピエロになって
Playing the role of the assigned clown,
シリアスはもう消し去っていいよ
you can throw away all the seriousness now.
お前を包む喧騒
The hustle and bustle surrounding you.
逃げられるのに掴めない
I can escape, yet I can't grasp it.
水のように透き通る溜め息
A sigh as transparent as water.
どうしようもない
There's nothing I can do.
忘れかけてた
I was starting to forget.
忘れてきたはずの宵闇
The twilight I was supposed to have left behind.
頭に響くカテドラル
A cathedral echoing in my head.
迷いもなく 振り向かない
No hesitation, and I won't look back.
目に見えない Many Many Moment
An invisible many, many moment.
Wow 超常的
Wow, so supernatural.
くだらない いつ笑って
How absurd, laughing all the time,
惑わせ 有象無象
deceiving the rabble.
勝手にふかれ
Letting the wind blow as it pleases,
目に物見せてやれ Fade out
I'll show them what I'm made of. Fade out.
焦がれたって始まんねえ
Longing for it won't change anything.
火を灯せ Pheromone Pheromone
Light the fire, pheromone, pheromone.
差し迫って 歌って お好きなの
Pressured to sing whatever you like.
Catch me if you can baby
Chewy Chew, Chewy Chew
もぐもぐもぐ
Munch, munch, munch.
Chewy Chew, Chewy Chew
目を合わせ 何度も交わし合ったメロディ
Locking eyes, a melody we exchanged over and over.
騙されたまま居たいわ
I want to remain deceived.
退屈なのはお互い様
We're both bored anyway.
傷は癒えぬまま居たいわ
I want to keep the wounds unhealed.
消えちゃって ねえ
Just fade away, hey.
眼差し避けてみないふり
Avoiding your gaze, pretending not to see.
帰る場所はどこだったっけ
Where was the place I was supposed to return to?
真っ新で 傷一つねえ
Brand new, without a single scratch.
格好良い態度で 今、吠えきって
With a cool attitude, howl with all your might right now.
後片付けも曖昧でも 口数揃えて
Even if the cleanup is vague, aligning our words,
立ち振る舞いしちゃ落ち着かないでしょう
behaving like that must feel so restless, right?
あわよくば今すぐ豹変する
If all goes well, I'll transform right now.
その言葉は見通しだ全部
I can see right through all of those words.
おどけて見せようが
No matter how much I play the fool...
この傷跡をそっと撫でる
I gently caress this scar.
大したことないと思うなら
If you think it's no big deal,
受け止めてよ ほら 息を止めて
then accept it. Look, hold your breath.
くだらない いつ笑って
How absurd, laughing all the time,
惑わせ 有象無象
deceiving the rabble.
勝手にふかれ
Letting the wind blow as it pleases,
目に物見せてやれ Fade out
I'll show them what I'm made of. Fade out.
焦がれたって始まんねえ
Longing for it won't change anything.
火を灯せ Pheromone Pheromone
Light the fire, pheromone, pheromone.
差し迫って 歌って お好きなの
Pressured to sing whatever you like.
Catch me if you can baby
どうしたい？
What do you want to do?
ってもう見飽きた
I'm already tired of that.
差し伸べないで
Don't reach your hand out to me.
抱いていて 甘えちゃうわ
Just hold me, I'll end up spoiled.
頭爆発しそうな自分よ
I feel like my head is about to explode,
あなたを縛る時代よ
in an era that binds you.
I don't care
So don't care
このJourney on way
on this journey.
くだらない いつ笑って
How absurd, laughing all the time,
惑わせ 有象無象
deceiving the rabble.
勝手にふかれ
Letting the wind blow as it pleases,
目に物見せてやれ Fade out
I'll show them what I'm made of. Fade out.
焦がれたって始まんねえ
Longing for it won't change anything.
火を灯せ Pheromone Pheromone
Light the fire, pheromone, pheromone.
差し迫って 歌って お好きなの
Pressured to sing whatever you like.
Catch me if you can baby
Chewy Chew, Chewy Chew
もぐもぐもぐ
Munch, munch, munch.
Chewy Chew, Chewy Chew
目を合わせ 何度も交わし合ったメロディ
Locking eyes, a melody we exchanged over and over.
この道はどこへ続いているのだろう？
[Text: Where does this road lead to?]
目の前に
[Text: Right in front of my eyes]
無数に
[Text: Countless]
別れた
[Text: divided]
可能性が広がっている。
[Text: possibilities are spreading out.]
ワタシは、私であるために
[Text: To be who I am,]
自分を縛る言葉は捨てて、広がっていくのは
[Text: I discard the words that bind me, and what spreads out is]
私だけの、まだ知らない光。
[Text: my very own, yet unknown light.]
10.29 ARIAKE ARENA
[Text: 10.29 ARIAKE ARENA]
Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live SHINIER
[Text: Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live SHINIER]
進め。輝き溢れる、光の先へ。
[Text: Go forward. Towards the overflowing brilliance, beyond the light.]
はい！
Yes!
みなさん、なんと！
Everyone, guess what!
えー、常闇トワのセカンドソロライブが決定しましたー！
Umm... Tokoyami Towa's second solo live has been confirmed!
いぇーい！
Yay!
おらー！来たぞー！
Yeah! It's here!
ついに公開された！
It's finally been announced!
よかったー！
Thank goodness!
ここまで色々あったんですけども
A lot of things happened to get here,
まだ、ここが始まり、なんだけど
but this is still just the beginning.
頑張りますからね
I'll do my absolute best!
どうでした？びっくりしました？
How was it? Were you surprised?
ありがとう！ありがとう、ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you, thank you so much!
泣きそう？
Are you about to cry?
わかる。
I get it.
ちょっと、泣きそうなの分かりますわ。
I can totally tell you're holding back tears.
一緒。
Me too.
でも、とっておきましょう。それは、みなさん
But let's save those tears. Everyone...
今じゃないわ。
now is not the time.
とっとこう、本番までに。
Let's save them for the actual show.
えー、ということで、今回のね、ライブタイトルは、Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live SHIN...
So, the title of this live show is Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live SHIN...
「SHINier」です。
It's "SHINier".
え、こちらなんですが、さっき発表したアルバムのね、タイトル「しん」に繋がっているんですよね。
This actually connects to the title of the album I just announced, "SHIN".
このね、え、アルバムなんですけれども、色々な「しん」が入っているアルバムとなってまして、
This album contains various "SHIN" (scenes/beliefs/aspects)...
その、えー、「しん」に沿って今回の、えー、ライブタイトルも、えー、「SHINier」という風に、えー、つけさせていただきました。
...so following those "SHIN", I decided to name this concert "SHINier".
えー、ファーストライブのね、えー、「Screaming」よりも、えー、もっと輝いて、かっこいい、
Even more than my first live, "Screaming," I want to shine brighter, be cooler...
えー、無限大の可能性を皆さんにお届けするので、えー、ぜひ見に来てくれればなと思います。
...and deliver infinite possibilities to all of you, so please come and see it!
はい、え、そしてキービジュアル見てみましょう！
Alright, now let's take a look at the key visual!
はい、どうですか？こちらね、えー、アルバムのジャケット写真描いていただいた花邑まいさんにね、えー、キービジュアルも一緒に描いていただきました。めっちゃかっこいいよね！
Yes! How do you like it? This key visual was illustrated by Mai Hanamura, who also drew my album cover! It's so cool, right?
さっきのはちょっと黒い、暗い感じだったんだけど、こっちはね、光がね、見えるような感じで、
The previous one had a darker feel, but this one shows the light coming through.
えー、進んでいくような、えー、前に行けるような明るさを、えー、演出してもらいましたね。
She created a brightness that makes you feel like you're moving forward.
すごいもう、クールでかっこいいけど、みたいな感じを出せれば、と思っております。衣装もお気に入りです。
I wanted to convey a feeling of "cool and stylish, but also..." The outfit is also one of my favorites!
えー、当日楽しみです。
I'm really looking forward to the day of the live!
えー、そして、えー、今回のハッシュタグは、ライブ、アルバムどちらも共通で、えー、ハッシュタグ「#常山」…あ、「常山」だって、常闇…
And the hashtag for this event, both for the live and the album, is #Tokoyama... Ah, I said Tokoyama! Tokoyami...
自分お名前噛むって凄くない？
Isn't it crazy to stumble over my own name?
いや、なんかスタッフさんにめっちゃ見られて、笑ってんだけど。恥ずかしいんだけど！
The staff are all staring and laughing at me. This is so embarrassing!
えー、#常闇トワ2nd です。
The hashtag is #常闇トワ2nd.
もう帰りたい！ねえ、笑いすぎだから！
I wanna go home! Hey, you guys are laughing way too much!
えー、じゃあ、今日から改名して「常山」になります。よろしくお願いいたします。
Okay, I'm renaming myself to "Tokoyama" starting today. Pleased to meet you.
えー、皆さん、いっぱいね、ポストしてくれればなと思います。
Everyone, please post a lot using the hashtag!
そして、えー、皆さん、お待ちかね、チケット情報です！
And now, here is the ticket information you've all been waiting for!
本当に耳赤くなるんだけど。
My ears are seriously turning red.
えー、会場はなんと！
The venue is...
えー、有明アリーナです！
Ariake Arena!
はい。えー、前回よりもね、もうすごい、何倍？3倍？2.5倍？
Yes! Compared to last time, it's like... how many times bigger? 3 times? 2.5 times?
くらいね、えー、会場も広くなって、前回あんなに緊張して、最初震えてたのに、
The venue has gotten so much bigger. Even though I was so nervous and shaking at the start last time...
あの、だ、だい、大丈夫かなっていう心配で。
...I'm worried like, "will I... will I be okay?"
でも、あの、全然実感沸かなかったんですけど、この、今この配信してちょっと実感が沸いてきて、ぷるぷるしてきました。ドキドキします。でも、頑張ります。
Honestly, it didn't feel real at all, but doing this stream is making it sink in, and I'm starting to shake. My heart is pounding. But I'll do my best!
えー、チケットは、SS席、S席、A席、B席の4種類です。
There are four ticket tiers: SS seat, S seat, A seat, and B seat.
えー、こちらのね、SS席が気になってると思うんですけれども、
I'm sure you're all curious about the SS seat.
SS席というのは、SHINier Supporterの略で、SHINierはトワのことで、そのサポーターは皆様のことなんですよね。
SS seat stands for "SHINier Supporter". "SHINier" refers to Towa, and the "Supporter" is all of you!
はい。そしてね、SS席には特典で、ブレスレットライトがついてきます！
Yes, and as a special benefit, the SS seat comes with a Bracelet Light!
ちょっとお高いかもしれないんですけれども、このね、席とかね、ブレスレットライトがね、ついてくる点を考えると、
It might be a bit pricey, but when you consider the seating and the fact that it comes with a Bracelet Light...
もう、目の前で爆音で聴いてほしいなっていう感じなんですけども。
...I really want you to experience the booming sound right in front of you.
このブレスレットライト、すごい作りたかったものなので、作れて本当に嬉しいです。
This Bracelet Light is something I really wanted to make, so I'm so happy we could do it.
えー、ライブロゴやタイトルが入っている特別仕様で、えー、紫色の上部がマグネットになっていて、付け外しができるようになっております。
It has a special design featuring the concert logo and title, and the purple clasp is magnetic, making it easy to attach and detach.
点灯カラーは白色になっておりまして、SS席のサポーターの皆様はこれで会場全体をキービジュアルみたいに光り輝かせていただければなと思います。
The light color is white, so I hope the SS seat supporters can use this to light up the venue like the key visual!
あの、すっごいいっぱいあるからさ、あの、頑張ってんね、今。
There's so much info to go through, so I'm doing my best here!
えー、じゃあね、気になる各座席のエリアマップ見てみましょう。どんなもんじゃい、ということで、はい！
Alright, let's look at the seating map that everyone is curious about. What does it look like? Here it is!
そうなんです。SS席はなんとステージのど真ん中にあります！
That's right! The SS seats are located right in front of the stage!
で、その周りをS席、えー、A席、B席という風に、えー、周りを囲んでいる形ですね。
And surrounding it are the S seats, A seats, and B seats, wrapping around the center.
えー、現地チケットはこのあと21時から1次抽選の申し込みが始まるので、みんなぜひ応募してください！
Applications for the first round of ticket lottery will start today at 9 PM, so please make sure to apply!
えー、海外の皆様も買えますので、よろしくお願いします。
Supporters overseas can also purchase them, so please look forward to it!
Overseas bro! Yes! Everyone, let's buy, let's go, let's go! Yes!
と、いうわけで、でも現地に行けないよって人も大丈夫！
But even if you can't make it to the venue, don't worry!
えー、配信チケットもあります！
Streaming tickets are also available!
えー、こちらもね、21時から発売開始なので、えー、特設サイトをチェックしてみてください！
These will also go on sale starting at 9 PM, so please check the special website!
えー、概要欄にも、更新してくれてると思うんですけども、リンクがありますので、
I believe the link has been added to the description box below, so...
えー、あるけど、あるけどね、「常闇トワ セカンドライブ」で検索してもサイトが出てくるので、ブックマークしておくといいかもしれません。ちょっと出るか検索してみて、ちょっと心配だから。
...although, you can also just search for "Tokoyami Towa Second Live" to find the site, so bookmarking it might be a good idea. Please try searching for it to see if it shows up, because I'm a bit worried.
はい、配信でも、現地でも、どちらもかっこいい、えー、みんなが喜んでくれる、喜んでくれるようなパフォーマンスを頑張ってしたいと思うので、
Whether you watch it online or at the venue, I'll do my absolute best to put on a cool performance that will make everyone happy, so...
トワ頑張って走り抜けたいと思います！
I will do my best to run all the way through!
はい、そしてここまであっという間だったんですが
Yes, and it's flown by so quickly up to this point,
今回のライブ情報はここまでになります！
but that's all the concert info we have for now!
あれ？何かライブに必要なものが足りなくない？
"Wait, isn't there something missing that we need for the concert?"
って思ったそこの眷属！
If you Kenzoku out there were thinking that...
すごいカメラが大変だったんで、あまり動かないようにしますけど
Since the camera was struggling, I'll try not to move too much.
ライブグッズは現在、準備中になります！
Concert merchandise is currently in preparation!
またね、別の日に、ライブグッズを発表する枠も取りたいと思いますから
On another day, I'd like to do a stream to announce the concert goods,
お楽しみに待っていてください！
so please look forward to it and wait!
貯金のタイムだからね。いい？皆さん貯金タイム。
It's saving time, okay? Everyone, save up.
と思いきや！
Or so you thought!
ここまでがライブの告知。
That was just the concert announcement.
で、貯金タイムって言ったんだけど、ここからは貯金しないでほしいタイムです！
I said it's saving time, but from here, it's the "please don't save" time!
常闇トワ誕生日記念2025のグッズ発売告知となります！
This is the announcement for Tokoyami Towa's Birthday Celebration 2025 merchandise!
どーん！見てください、こちら！
Tada! Check this out!
イェーイ！rurudoマミーにイラスト描いてもらっちゃいました！
Yay! I got Rurudo-mommy to draw the illustration for us!
マミーありがとう！
Thank you, Mommy!
可愛いよね！
It's so cute, isn't it?
詳細をみんなで見ていこうと思います！こちら！
Let's take a look at the details together! Here it is!
じゃじゃん！そう、これマミーに描いてもらった
Tada! Yes, this illustration Mommy drew for me...
ゴシックな部屋の撮影のトワちゃん。
...features Towa in a gothic room photoshoot.
で、ちょっとrurudoマミーの若干性癖がどこかに詰まってるんで
And since Rurudo-mommy's fetishes are packed in here somewhere...
どこか当ててくださいね。
...please try to guess where they are!
はい、そしてこちら！ビッグタオル！
Next, we have this! Big Towel!
Mr.Lime先生に描いていただきました！
This was drawn by Mr.Lime-sensei!
ライム先生いつもありがとう！
Lime-sensei, thank you as always!
この配信のサムネも描いてくれました。ありがとういつも！
He also drew the thumbnail for this stream. Thanks as always!
昔からずっと描いてくださってる先生です。
He's been drawing for me for a very long time.
はい、こちらもビッグサイズのタオル、ぜひ使ってくれればなと思います。
Yes, this is a big-sized towel, so I hope you'll use it.
続いてはこちら、ぽん！
Next up is this, pop!
トワ様とお出かけぬいぐるみキーホルダー！
Towa-sama to Odekake Plushie Keychain!
これはですね、やっぱトワちゃんね、
This one, well, you know how Towa...
結構毎月「トワべる」っていうのでみんなが
...hosts the monthly "Towavel" hashtag, where everyone...
トワのぬいぐるみと一緒に結構旅行してくれて、それを
...takes Towa's plushies on trips and shares them,
行った気持ちになる配信があるんですけど、
...which we look at in a stream to feel like we traveled too.
やっぱ私服で、ちょっとデートというか、まあデートとしてやってもいい、
So, so you can take it out in casual clothes, wait, like a date? Yes, you can treat it as a date.
っていう意味を込めて私服のミニチュアサイズというか、持ち運びできるようなお出かけぬいぐるみキーホルダーを作らせていただきましたので、
With that in mind, we made this portable, miniature-sized plushie keychain of me in casual clothes.
また買って届いたら、いっぱいね、投稿してくれればなと思います！
So please buy it, and once it arrives, share lots of posts with it!
はい、そしてこちら！
Next up is this!
眷属メタルキーホルダー！
Kenzoku Metal Keychain!
可愛いビビと、あとはトワやっぱりね、
It features a cute Bibi, and also, Towa, you know...
歌ももちろん大好きなんですけど、
...of course loves singing, but...
ゲームもやっぱりすごく好き、
...I also really love gaming,
なんで、そのイメージをこちらに詰め込んでいただきました。
...so we packed that concept into this item as well.
可愛いでしょ、キーホルダー。
It's a really cute keychain, right?
最近トワね、色んなところにキーホルダーをじゃらじゃらつけるのはまってるんで、
Recently, I've been into jangling tons of keychains on everything,
作ってみました！よろしくお願いいたします。
so I decided to make one! Please check it out.
フルセットの購入特典もございますので見てみましょう！
We also have purchase bonuses for the full set, so let's take a look!
はい！rurudoマミーの、
Yes! We have Rurudo-mommy's illustration,
ちょっとぺろっみたいな表情差分があるトワちゃんの、
featuring Towa with a slightly playful tongue-out facial expression...
箔押し複製サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきます！
...which comes as a bromide card with a hot-stamped replica signature!
はい、フルセット買うとついてくるんだよ、これが。
Yes, you get this if you buy the full set!
でもね、そしてね、しかもね、
But wait, there's more, and guess what?
なんと、もう一個ついてきちゃうの。こちら！
Unbelievably, you get one more thing! Here it is!
戻ってね。あ、これだった。ごめん。
Ah, let's go back... Ah, it was this one. Sorry.
あ、これか。フルセットはこれ。
Ah, this one? The full set is this.
はい、これ。1, 2, 3, 4, 5
Yes, this. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 items.
これで、これがついてきて、
These are included, and then...
で、これ。これがついてくる。次！
...this. This is what you get next!
これこれこれこれ！
This, this, this, this!
もうオート流ししながらこれ。
Going through the auto-slides, here it is!
これがついてきます。カードがね、ついてきますよ。
You get this. Yes, a card is included!
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEで使用できるカードが1枚同梱！
One card that can be used in the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME is included!
カードはね、ホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入された方のみ対象となっております。
The card is only eligible for those who purchase from the Hololive Production Official Shop.
特典に付くのは、推しをアピールできる「キーカード」「推しホロメンバーカード」です。
The bonus included is a "Key Card" / "Oshi Holomem Card" to show off your favorite.
カードの詳細や遊び方についてはホームページで確認してね。
For details and how to play the card game, please check the official website.
ということで、以上、常闇トワ誕生日記念グッズの情報でした！
And that's all for the Tokoyami Towa Birthday Celebration merchandise info!
みんな買ってね！
Everyone, please buy them!
これで素敵なMV作るんだから、買ってくれないといいの作れないから！
I'm going to make a wonderful MV with this funding, so if you don't buy it, I can't make a good one!
よろしくお願いします！
So please support me!
はい、そしてそして、先ほどお伝えした、
And next, as mentioned earlier,
セカンドアルバム『Symphony』がホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップでの発売が先行して、
pre-orders for the 2nd Album "Shyn" have started early...
開始しております！
...on the Hololive Production Official Shop!
はい、多分、配信画面の下に出ていた購入ボタンから発売ページに飛べるようになってると思うんですけど、
Yes, you should be able to jump to the store page from the purchase button displayed below the stream, but...
皆さん更新されました？
did it refresh for you?
し、あの、もしなかったらね、更新でおねがいいたします。更新してください。
If not, please refresh the page. Please refresh it.
購入ボタンをクリックする前に注意事項なんですが、
Before you click the buy button, here is a quick note:
セカンドアルバムとそれ以外のものを同じカートで購入していただいた場合に、
If you purchase the 2nd album and other items together in the same cart,
発売日の10月8日までに発送が行えない可能性があるので気をつけてください。
they might not be shipped by the release date of October 8th, so please be careful.
セカンドアルバム単体での購入なら大丈夫です。
If you purchase the 2nd album by itself, it's totally fine.
ありがとう！買ったありがとう、ありがとうね！
Thank you! To those who bought it, thank you so much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ホロライブ公式以外でのご購入...
For purchases outside the official Hololive shop...
まあ、この後9時からになりますからね。
Well, it starts at 9:00 PM after this.
ありがとう！祝ってくれてありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you so much for celebrating!
はい！そして、もうあと少し！
Yes! And just a little more!
この後、8時50分、
After this, at 8:50 PM,
「ちゅいちゅい」のMVプレミア公開がありまして、
the "Chui Chui" MV will have its premiere,
えー、9時からライブチケットの発売がございます！
and live concert tickets will go on sale at 9:00 PM!
ということで、今日は1時間枠じゃなくてちょっと短いんですけれども、
So, today's stream wasn't a full hour and was a bit short,
こんな感じで、また後日配信すると思うので、
but I'll stream again on a later date,
ぜひ、また遊びに来てください！
so please come hang out again!
はい、では皆さん、
Alright then, everyone,
この後、「ちゅいちゅい」...
after this, "Chui Chui"...
ここにいたら、すぐ聴けるんで、
If you stay here, you can watch it right away.
かっこいいMV聴けるんで、
You can watch the cool MV,
ここに待機して、しばし待たれよ！
so wait right here and hang tight!
ということで、今日は...
With that said, today...
ありがとう！いっぱいポストしてね！
thank you! Be sure to post a lot of tweets!
駆け足になっちゃった！
I had to rush through it!
またねー！
See ya!
常闇トワ 生誕祭 / 重々発表あり!!
[Tokoyami Towa Birthday Festival / Major Announcements!!]